<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://blog.allaway.tech/</id><title>blog.allaway.tech</title><subtitle>A minimal, responsive, and powerful Jekyll theme for presenting professional writing.</subtitle> <updated>2024-07-11T16:49:46+01:00</updated> <author> <name>ian</name> <uri>https://blog.allaway.tech/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.allaway.tech/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://blog.allaway.tech/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2024 ian </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>How to disable the DHCP server on a TP-link Deco mesh network</title><link href="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/tp-link-deco-dhcp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to disable the DHCP server on a TP-link Deco mesh network" /><published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-08-03T01:46:59+01:00</updated> <id>https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/tp-link-deco-dhcp/</id> <content src="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/tp-link-deco-dhcp/" /> <author> <name>ian</name> </author> <category term="Networking" /> <category term="DHCP" /> <summary> How to disable the DHCP server on a TP-link Deco mesh network I recently moved house and, for the first time ever, was able to upgraded my broadband to fibre to the premises. This is great, and I now have a superfast internet connection. Only problem being that my old pfSense firewall/router cannot keep up with how fast it now needs to route the traffic. When I did the original pfSense install... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to change some batteries in under 10s</title><link href="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/battery-change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to change some batteries in under 10s" /><published>2022-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-11-04T00:45:12+00:00</updated> <id>https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/battery-change/</id> <content src="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/battery-change/" /> <author> <name>ian</name> </author> <category term="Theatre sound" /> <category term="Sound No. 2" /> <summary> How to change some batteries in under 10s I know this might not seem the most impressive thing but how many people could actually change the batteries in a device they have this quickly? It definitely takes my wife longer than this to even get the battery cover off the TV remote. Some backstory As I have alluded to many times my full time job is working as a Theatre Sound No. 1 on a show in Lo... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Home Assistant Alexa smart home integration over Cloudflare</title><link href="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/home-assistant-alexa-cloudflare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home Assistant Alexa smart home integration over Cloudflare" /><published>2022-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-10-15T01:16:17+01:00</updated> <id>https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/home-assistant-alexa-cloudflare/</id> <content src="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/home-assistant-alexa-cloudflare/" /> <author> <name>ian</name> </author> <category term="Home Assistant" /> <category term="Cloudflare" /> <summary> Today I decided it was the day that I was going to manage to get Alexa to talk to my Home Assistant (HA). There are a couple of things that made this slightly difficult for me. The first was that I had limited access to my domain only to the UK. The second was a setting I didn’t even know was on but after finding it I didn’t want to turn it off. Something that made it a little hard to track dow... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Restarting the blog</title><link href="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/coming-back/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Restarting the blog" /><published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-06-29T01:21:16+01:00</updated> <id>https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/coming-back/</id> <content src="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/coming-back/" /> <author> <name>ian</name> </author> <category term="About" /> <category term="blogging" /> <summary> Unfortunately, I have not been blogging over the last 6 months or so. This is because I have returned to my full-time job on the West End and due to many Covid complications I have not had the time or the will to be blogging. Now that we have now bedded into our second cast and things are running much more smoothly, I have a bit more time on my hands. I am currently working on a post about my f... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Controlling Blackmagic Design Smart Videohubs from QLab</title><link href="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/blackmagic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Controlling Blackmagic Design Smart Videohubs from QLab" /><published>2021-10-15T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-10-15T01:15:22+01:00</updated> <id>https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/blackmagic/</id> <content src="https://blog.allaway.tech/posts/blackmagic/" /> <author> <name>ian</name> </author> <category term="qlab" /> <category term="blackmagic" /> <summary> Controlling Blackmagic Design Smart Videohubs from QLab is always a little bit difficult. There are network cues built into QLab but the required TCP cue does not exist. However, it is fairly simple to create a python script to give us this functionality and call that from within an Back in the summer of 2021, I was working on a small show that used eight cameras recording into eight Blackmagi... </summary> </entry> </feed>
